<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<commands>
    <command>
        <name>CREATE</name>
        <description>
            Commands to create tables. Input includes table name, column descriptions (names and data types),
            and constraints (PRIMARY KEY, FOREIGN KEY, UNIQUE, NOT NULL, CHECK).
        </description>
        <example>
            CREATE TABLE students (
                id INTEGER PRIMARY KEY,
                name STRING NOT NULL,
                age INTEGER,
                grade STRING
            );
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>ALTER</name>
        <description>
            Commands to modify the structure of existing tables. Input includes table name, columns to modify,
            new column names, and new constraints.
        </description>
        <example>
            ALTER TABLE students ADD COLUMN email STRING;
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>DROP</name>
        <description>
            Commands to delete tables. Input includes the name of the table to be deleted.
        </description>
        <example>
            DROP TABLE students;
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>SELECT</name>
        <description>
            Commands to retrieve data from tables. Input includes table name, list of columns to select, filter conditions,
            sorting parameters, and row limit.
        </description>
        <example>
            SELECT name, age FROM students WHERE grade = 'A' ORDER BY age;
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>INSERT</name>
        <description>
            Commands to insert data into tables. Input includes table name, list of columns, and corresponding values.
        </description>
        <example>
            INSERT INTO students (name, age, grade) VALUES ('John Doe', 20, 'A');
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>UPDATE</name>
        <description>
            Commands to update data in tables. Input includes table name, columns to update, new values, and filter conditions.
        </description>
        <example>
            UPDATE students SET grade = 'B' WHERE name = 'John Doe';
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>DELETE</name>
        <description>
            Commands to delete data from tables. Input includes table name and filter conditions to determine which records to delete.
        </description>
        <example>
            DELETE FROM students WHERE age &lt; 18;
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>BEGIN</name>
        <description>
            Commands to start a transaction. Input may include transaction labels or other parameters if necessary.
        </description>
        <example>
            BEGIN TRANSACTION;
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>COMMIT</name>
        <description>
            Commands to commit a transaction. Input includes confirmation of transaction completion.
        </description>
        <example>
            COMMIT;
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>ROLLBACK</name>
        <description>
            Commands to roll back a transaction. Input includes specifying the transaction to be rolled back.
        </description>
        <example>
            ROLLBACK;
        </example>
    </command>
    <command>
        <name>CONSTRAINTS</name>
        <description>
            Constraints and Validation:
            Input data for insertion and update are checked for compliance with established constraints.
            data types:

                - INTEGER,
                - STRING,
                - BOOLEAN,
                - REAL.

            integrity constraints:

                - NOT NULL,
                - UNIQUE,
                - PRIMARY KEY,
                - FOREIGN KEY,
                - CHECK.

            by default all constraints have name like 'constraint_name_column_constraint'
        </description>
    </command>
</commands>
